Guide to the Crawford Theater Collection
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
- Clippings, 1800-1980; Series IV; 168.5 linear feet (132 boxes)
  - Scrapbooks
    - Two albums of magazine clippings of photographs and drawings of performers, 1890s (Box 437)
    - Album of German playbills, 1887-1892 (Box 438)
    - Album of German playbills and clippings, 1896-1903 (Box 438)
    - Album of clippings and programs of U.S. productions and performers, 1890-1910s (Box 438)
    - Emerson (collector) Loose scrapbook pages of photographs, letters, clippings, etc. regarding minstrels, 1880-1910s (Box 439)
    - Loose photographs and clippings of minstrels, 1800s (Box 440)
    - Forstell, A. L. and Emerson (collectors) Album of photographs, programs and clippings of Jeppe and Fanny Delano and the Peak Family, Circa 1870-1890 (Box 440)
    - Emerson (collector) Album of photographs, letters, playbills and programs regarding U.S. theatre productions, 1860-1870 (Box 440)
    - Three albums (IV, V, and VII) of programs with comments and clippings, 1920-1931 (Box 441)
    - Album of magazine and press clippings regarding Shakespearean and other productions, 1918-1924 (Box 442)
    - Album of clippings and programs of New York City productions, 1908-1909 (Box 442)
    - Album of miscellaneous magazine clippings and programs, Circa 1900 (Box 443)
    - Loose pages of miscellaneous clippings, Circa 1880 (Box 443)
    - Album of magazine clippings of actresses, 1890-1910 (Box 444)
    - Hull, Josephine (collector) Album of programs and clippings of U.S. productions, 1910-1920 (Box 444)
    - Album of miscellaneous magazine clippings, Circa 1920-1930 (Box 444)
    - Album of playbills and programs of New York City and other productions, 1840-1880 (Box 445)
    - Album of programs and clippings of New York, New Haven and other U.S. productions, 1915-1932 (Box 446)
    - Album of programs from London, 1909-1911 (Box 446a)
    - Album of programs from London, 1912-1913 (Box 446b)
    - Album of clippings and financial notes relating to circus performances of the Ducrow and Laverne families, Circa 1880s-1890s (Box 446b)
    - Album of programs from Boston, miscellaneous United States, and miscellaneous Europe, 1884-1892 (Box 446c)
    - Album of programs and clippings from amateur productions in Boston and Boston area, 1907-1916 undated (Box 446c)
    - Album of programs from Boston and Boston area, 1900-1904 (Box 446d)
    - Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs and drawings from Boston and Boston area, 1899-1915 (Box 446d)
    - Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs and drawings from Boston, 1904-1906, undated (Box 446e)
    - Album of programs and clippings from Boston, miscellaneous United States, and India, 1904-1906, undated (Box 446e)
    - Moeller, Mrs. H. L. (collector) Album of programs from New Haven, New York, and unidentified locations, 1913-1917, undated (Box 446f)
    - Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs and drawings from New Haven, New York, Springfield, MA, and miscellaneous Europe, 1893-1915 (Box 446g)
    - Album of programs and clippings from New Haven and New York theaters, 1914-1917 (Box 446h)
    - Album of programs and clippings from New York theaters, 1869-1880 April (Box 446i)
    - Album of programs and clippings from New York, miscellaneous United States, London, and Paris, 1880 May-1902 (Box 446i)
    - Album of programs and clippings from Baltimore, Chicago, Cleveland, New York, Mexico, and unidentified theaters, 1885-1901 (Box 446j)
    - Album of programs, clippings, clippings of photographs and drawings, and ticket stubs from New York, miscellaneous United States, France, Great Britain, and Spain, 1906-1915 (Box 446j)
    - Cowles, Mrs. Philip (collector) Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs and drawings from Albany, Boston, Kansas City, MO, Springfield, MA, and miscellaneous United States, 1896-1929 (Box 446k)
    - Wiles, Bertha Helena (collector) Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs and drawings from Albany, Chicago, New York City, miscellaneous New York state, and Switzerland, 1885-1896 (Box 446l)
    - Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs and drawings from Boston, New Hampshire, New York City, miscellaneous United States, and England, 1915-1925 January 9 (Box 446m)
    - Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs and drawings from New York, miscellaneous United States, and miscellaneous South America, 1925 January 10-1929 (Box 446m)
    - Koehler, Jerome H. (collector) Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs and drawings from New Haven and New York, 1896-1897 April 6, 1897 April 7-1898 April 18, 1898 April 30-1899 April 22, 1900 December 31-1901 December 31, 1904 May-1906 February (Box 446n)
    - Koehler, Jerome H. (collector) Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs and drawings from New York City, miscellaneous New York state, and Philadelphia, 1907-1908 February (Box 446n)
    - Koehler, Jerome H. (collector) Album of programs and ticket stubs from New York, 1910-1911 March (Box 446n)
    - Koehler, Jerome H. (collector) Album of programs, clippings of photographs, and ticket stubs from New York, Belgium, and France, 1912-1913 (Box 446n)
    - Koehler, Jerome H.(collector) Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs from Boston and New York, 1915-1916 (Box 446n)
    - Koehler, Jerome H. (collector) Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs from Boston, New York, and Australia, 1919-1920, 1926 (Box 446n)
    - Koehler, Jerome H. (collector) Index to preceding and other (missing) volumes, 1888-1926 (Box 446n)
    - Remington, M. (collector) Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs from Boston, New York, Providence, and London, 1887-1896, 1902-1914 (Box 446o)
    - Album of programs, clippings of photographs and drawings, and (personal) photographs, unidentified locations, 1864, 1883-1886, 1907 (Box 446o)
    - Album of programs and clippings from Boston and Washington, D. C., 1890-1898 (Box 446o)
    - Album of clippings and autographs, 1902-1903, undated (Box 446o)
    - Katz, Beatrice Spitzer (collector) Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs from Chicago, New Jersey, New York City, London, and Germany, 1911-1921 November 21 (Box 446p)
    - Katz, Beatrice Spitzer (collector) Album of programs, clippings, and clippings of photographs from New Haven and New York, 1921 November 28-1926 January 26 (Box 446p)
    - Katz, Beatrice Spitzer (collector) Album of programs from New York, 1926 Jna 26-1929 (Box 446p)
    - Katz, Beatrice Spitzer (collector) Album of programs from New York, 1930-1931 (Box 446p)
    - Thorburn, Grant (collector) Autographed programs and pictorial material from productions in New York and miscellaneous other cities
      - Volumes 1 - 5, 1903-1915 (Box 446q)
      - Volumes 6 - 10, 1915-1924 (Box 446r)
      - Volumes 11 - 15, 1924-1930 (Box 446s)
      - Volumes 16 - 20, 1931-1944 (Box 446t)
      - Index to autographs (A - H) (Box 446u)
      - Index to autographs (I - R) (Box 446v)
      - Index to autographs (S - Z) (Box 446w)
- Miscellanea, 1850-1980; Series V; 24.25 linear feet (52 boxes)
  This series contains printed material, clippings, pictorial material, and miscellanea relating to the theater and performing arts, arranged alphabetically by topic.
  General
  The following materials formering in this series were interfiled or transferred: "Burlesque" originally in Series V, Box 452 was interfiled into Series I; "Sheet music" originally in Series V, boxes 475-477, was transferred to the Music Library, Yale University; "Vaudeville: Emerson College" originally in Series V, boxes 493-494 was interfiled into Series I; "Yale-Rockefeller Theater" originally in Series V, boxes 495-496 was transferred to the Drama Library, Yale University.
  There are no boxes 452, 475-477, 493-496 in the series.
  - American Mime Theater (Box 447)
  - Burgess, Neil (Box 448–451)
  - Cheyney, Sheldon (Box 453)
  - Costumes (Box 454–456)
  - Disney, Walt: "Peter Pan" (Box 457)
  - Gilbert and Sullivan (Box 458)
  - Miagtrels: Emerson Collection (Box 459–460)
  - Moscow Art Theater (Box 461)
  - Motion picture stills and index cards (Box 462)
  - Photographs: foreign plays and miscellanea (Box 463–465)
  - Publicity material (Box 466)
  - Roadside Theater, Washington D.C. (Box 467)
  - Shakespeare, William (Box 468–470)
  - Shaw, George Bernard (Box 471–474)
  - Sterling Memorial Library reference requests (Box 478–479)
  - Theater
    - Contracts (Box 480–481)
    - Exhibits and publications (Box 482–483)
    - Exteriors (Box 484)
    - French (Box 485)
    - Paraphernalia (Box 486–488)
    - World War I and II (Box 489–490)
  - Toby Tent Show (Box 491)
  - Touring companies (Box 492)
  - Card file index to stage movement in 18th century drama (Box 497)
  - Indices
    - Boston Theater programs, 1838-1929 (Box 498–499)
    - United States, A-Z (Box 500–501)
    - Wilder: Crawford Theater Collection (Box 502)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 503)
  - Federal Theatre Project (Box 503a)
  - Individuals (Box 503a)
  - National Board of Review of Motion Pictures (Box 503a)
  - Performing arts schools and workshops (Box 503a)
  - Theatres (Box 503a)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 503a)
  - Motion picture publicity material (Box 503b)
  - Motion picture publicity material (Box 503c)
  - Circus, advertisements, miscellaneous (Box 503D)
- Printed Material, 1900-1980; Series VI; 7 linear feet (7 boxes)
  This series contains journals, magazines, and other publications relating to the performing arts.
  - Books plated for Crawford Theater Collection (Box 504–505)
  - The Cast (serial) (Box 506)
  - The Cast and Caste (serials) (Box 507)
  - Miscellaneous serial publications (Box 508–510)
- Additional material, Accession 2006-M-109
  This accession consists of programs and playbills from theaters, both well known, as well as local theater groups, in England and the United States. Materials are arranged by country, name of city within a country, and name of theater within a city.
  - England
    - London
      - Alhambra Theatre, 1936 July 7, 18 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      - Open Air Theatre, Regent's Park, 1936 summer (Box 1, Folder 2)
      - Savoy Theatre, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
      - Westminster Theatre, 1936 July 3 (Box 1, Folder 4)
      - "What's On?," London Week, vol. 2, nos. 41, 43, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Malvern [Eighth Malvern Theatre Festival], 1936 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Stratford-upon-Avon [Shakespeare Festival], 1936 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - United States
    - Connecticut
      - Avon, Players' Guild of Avon Old Farms, 1936 March 21, May 23 (Box 1, Folder 8)
      - Milford, Plymouth Playhouse, undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - New Haven
        - Shubert Theatre, 1934-1939, 1945-1947, undated (Box 1, Folder 10 - 19)
        - Sprague Memorial Hall, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 20)
    - Florida, recital at the Singing Tower, Lake Wales, 1939-1940 (Box 1, Folder 21)
    - Maine
      - Blue Hill
        - Kneisel Hall, 1937 August 1, 8 (Box 1, Folder 22)
        - Town Hall, n.y. August 18 (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Massachusetts, Tanglewood-Lenox, Berkshire Festival, 1946 summer (Box 1, Folder 24)
    - New York
      - Alvin Theatre, 1935 December, 1936 December 27 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - Belasco Theatre, 1937 November 8 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - Booth Theatre, 1936 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - Broadhurst Theatre, 1935 April 8 (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - Broadway Theatre, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - Cort Theatre, 1946 April 29 (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - Doris Humphrey/Charles Weidman and Dance Group, undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - Forty-Fourth Street Theatre, 1936 December 28 (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - French Theatre of New York, n.y. February 2 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - Guild Theatre, 1935 December 2 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - Longacre Theatre, 1935 December 23 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - Mansfield Theatre, 1945 March 25 (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - Martin Beck Theatre, 1937 February 1 (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - Maxine Elliott's Theatre, 1934 December 17 (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - National Theatre, 1934 December 10, 1939 March 27 (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - New York Times National Book Fair, 1937 November 5-21 (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - Plymouth Theatre, 1937 February 1, 1939 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - St. James Theatre, 1937 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - Sam S. Shubert Theatre, 1936 December 28 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - Town Hall, 1935 April 13 (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - Windsor Theatre, 1939 January 30 (Box 2, Folder 45)
    - Vermont
      - Bennington, Bennington School of the Dance [fifth festival], 1938 August (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Dorset, The Dorset Players, undated (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Manchester
        - Southern Vermont Artists, 1938, 1939, 1946 August-September (Box 2, Folder 48)
        - Vermont Symphony Orchestra, undated (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - Weston, Weston Playhouse, 1938, 1939 summer (Box 2, Folder 50)
    - Unidentified, undated (Box 2, Folder 51)
- Additional material, 1890-1928; Accession 2011-M-066
  This accession consists of four scrapbooks of photographs of Geraldine Farrar, actress and opera singer, who starred in several films for Goldwyn Pictures Corporation from 1918 to 1920; a playbill for "Jack Straw," by W. Somerset Maugham; playscripts by Alfred Sutro, H.C. DeMille and David Belasco, and John McGowan; and a portfolio of Hirschfield caricatures primarily of actors and actresses.
  - Photographs (Scrapbooks)
    - Two scrapbooks: photographs from the films, The Turn of the Wheel and The World and its Woman starring Geraldine Farrar, Circa 1918 - 1919 (Box 1)
    - Scrapbook: photographs of Geraldine Farrar, films unknown, Circa 1918 - 1920 (Box 2)
    - Scrapbook: photographs from the film, The World and its Woman starring Geraldine Farrar, Circa 1919 (Box 3)
  - Hirschfeld Folio, 1964 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Scripts & Playbill
    - Demille, H.C. and Belasco, David, Men and Women, A Play In four Acts (Act III missing), Circa 1890 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Maugham, W. Somerset, Jack Straw (playbill), 1908 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - McGowan, John
      - Revue Sketches (with marginalia), Undated (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Singin' the Blues (with marginalia), Undated (Box 5, Folder 4)
      - Excess Baggage (script and playbill), Circa 1928 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Sutro, Alfred, Mollentrave on Women, A Comedy In Three Acts - Acts I - III, Undated (Box 5, Folder 6-8)